Buddhist tradition first came
to the land of snow
佛教传统
是在公元前5世纪
in the 5th century A.D.
首次出现在雪域
The first Tibetan king to be touched
by the dharma
第一位受达摩大师
感化的藏王
was King Hathatha Rignamputsan.
是哈塔塔·日男菩萨王.
他还有他的继位者
都是众所周知的
He and succeeding kings
were collectively known
as the Happy Generations.
快乐传人.
Now, some historians place them
in a Water Snake year, 21 3 A.D.
现在, 有的历史学家认为
他是公元前水蛇年213年出生的.
Others in the year of a Water Ox,
1 73 A.D.
其他学者则认为他是公元前水牛年173年,
出生的.
Amazing, isn't it?
The Happy Generations.
很神奇吧?
快乐传人.
Agent Cooper, l am thrilled to pieces
that the dharma came
库珀探员, 达摩大师转世
成为那个什么鬼呵呵呵国王
to King Ho-Ho-Ho, l really am,
真的很振奋人心,真的,
but l'm trying to focus
on the more immediate problems
但我更关心的是
目前的这个案子
of our own century here
in Twin Peaks.
还有我们自己的纪元
和双峰镇.
Albert, you'd be surprised
at the connection between the two.
艾伯特, 你会惊奇的发现
其实两者之间是有联系的.
Color me amazed.
少来忽悠我了.
Ronette Pulaski
has woken from her coma.
朗尼特·珀拉斯奇
已经醒过来了.
And?
然后呢?
l'm thinking she's gonna have
quite a story to tell,
我想她一定有很多话
要和我们说,
- when she regains the ability to speak.
- So she's not talking?
- 等她恢复语言能力的时候.
- 什么,她还不能说话?
Waking but silent, probably shock.
醒了但失语, 可能惊吓过度造成的.
l'm gonna show her the sketches
of Leo Johnson and Bob,
我会给她看里欧·强生
和鲍勃的人像素描,
the man Sarah Palmer saw
in her vision.
莎拉·帕尔默看到了
鲍勃的幻象.
The man who came to me
in my dream.
也曾经出现过
在我的梦里 .
Has anyone seen Bob on Earth
in the last few weeks?
过去几周到底有没有人
见过这个所谓的鲍勃?
No, not yet.
没有, 还没有.
Okay. l performed the autopsy
on Jacques Renault.
那好吧. 我对雅克·雷诺
进行了解剖.
Stomach contents revealed--
胃部的残余物显示--
Let's see.
--beer cans, a Maryland license plate,
我看看.
--啤酒馆, 一块马里兰州的车牌,
half a bicycle tire, a goat
and a small wooden puppet,
半条自行车胎, 一只山羊
和一个小木偶,
goes by the name of Pinocchio.
木偶皮诺曹.
You're making a joke.
你在捉弄我.
l like to think of myself
as one of the Happy Generations.
我这么有幽默感
就转世做快乐传人了.
And by the way,
the fat boy wasn't strangled.
啊还有,
那肥仔不是给勒死的.
Killer snuffed him with a pillow.
He was wearing gloves,
是给枕头闷死的.
凶手带着手套,
tape used to bind his wrists
was stolen
用来绑他手腕的带子
是从医院的
from the hospital supply closet.
That is it.
储物室里偷来的.
就这些了.
lf Jacques has any secrets
he'll be taking them underground.
如果雅克还有什么秘密
也只带着下葬了.
- What about the mill?
- Well, preliminary suggests arson.
- 锯木厂呢?
- 嗯, 初步确认是纵火案.
l nominate Leo Johnson.
我指证里欧·强生.
We'll have to get a statement
from Shelly Johnson.
那我们要给雪莉·强生
发一份指证书.
Hospital says she's well enough.
医院说她已经康复了.
How do you feel?
你感觉如何?
- Me?
- l believe it's customary to ask
- 我?
- 只是循例问一下而已
after the health of one
recently plugged three times.
一个给枪重创了
3下的人.
Thanks for asking.
谢谢关心.
- 少来耍感性啊.
- 谁开的枪, 艾伯特?
- Don't get sentimental.
- Who shot me, Albert?
My men are interrogating
the hotel guests,
我的人正在审问
酒店里的人,
the usual bumper crop
of rural know-nothings
收获不大
那些土佬什么都不知道
and drunken fly fishermen.
Nothing so far.
还有那个醉气熏天的卖鱼佬.
目前为止还没进展.
The world's most decrepit
room service waiter
那个
史上最老客服生
说那晚没发现
任何异常.
remembers nothing out of the ordinary
about the night.
No surprise there.
也没什么突破.
Senor Droolcup has, shall we say,
a mind that wanders.
也可以说,
朱凯先生那晚是在神游.
Albert, my ring is gone.
艾伯特, 我的戒指不见了.
One day here, the next day gone.
那天还在, 今天就没了.
So?
又如何?
l'm glad you're with us, Albert.
We need the very best.
很高兴你在，艾伯特.
我们这里需要人才.
Dedication to duty wasn't the only thing
that brought me back here, Cooper.
我可不光是回来这里
义务劳动的, 库珀.
- What else?
- Windom Earle.
- 那是什么?
- 伟顿·厄尔.
Agent Earle?
厄尔探员?
He's retired.
他不是退休了吗.
To a nice comfy chair
complete with wrist restraints
就在当地的喜剧学院
at the local laughing academy.
一张漂亮舒服有护腕的椅子上.
What happened?
发生什么事了?
Nobody knows.
没人知道.
Your former partner
flew the coop, Coop.
你的前搭档
秘密潜逃了, 库.
He escaped. Vanished into thin air.
他跑了. 消失得无影无踪.
That's not good.
情况不妙.
Hello?
你好?
Mrs. Tremond? Meals on Wheels.
屈梦太太? 我来送餐的.
Hello?
在吗?
Enter.
进来.
Mrs. Tremond?
屈梦太太?
Can l put your meal here?
放这里好吗?
Yes, that's fine.
好, 就放那吧.
Miss?
小姐?
Oh, hi.
哦, 你好.
Sometimes things
can happen just like this:
有时有些事可以
这样玩法:
Creamed corn.
奶油玉米.
你看见了吗
碟子里有奶油玉米?
Do you see creamed corn
on that plate?
Yes.
看见.
l requested no creamed corn.
我不要奶油玉米.
Do you see creamed corn
on that plate?
你看见了吗
碟子里有奶油玉米?
No.
没有.
My grandson is studying magic.
我孙子在学魔术.
That's nice.
那不错.
Who are you?
你是谁?
l'm taking over Laura Palmer's place
on the Meals on Wheels.
我是代替劳拉·帕尔默
来送餐的.
She's dead.
她死了.
你对她了解吗?
Did you know her well?
No.
不.
Okay, Mrs. Tremond.
那好, 屈梦太太.
l'll be back tomorrow to pick this up
and to bring your lunch.
我明天会过来给你送餐
顺便把这些收拾了.
They used to bring me
hospital food.
他们以前给我送
那些难吃的医院餐,
那个珍妮特.
lmagine that.
Young lady?
小姐?
You might ask Mr. Smith next door.
你可以问问住隔壁的史密斯先生.
He was Laura's friend.
他是劳拉的朋友.
Mr. Smith does not leave his house.
史密斯先生从不离开房子半步.
你好?
Hello?
她似乎是个不错的女生.
She seemed like a very nice girl.
Thanks, Harry.
谢谢, 哈里.
Ronette?
朗尼特?
l can't get this thing to work.
这椅子怎么搞的.
Excuse us, Ronette.
不好意思, 朗尼特.
"等等.
''Stop.
Read operating instructions
beneath seat before using.
使用前请阅读
椅子下面的操作说明.
Can't stand next to chair or stool.
不要站在凳子旁.
Do not remain seated.
不要坐在椅子上.
用脚踩着底座
Place foot on base
把椅子完全拉起
and pull seat all the way up
until you hear a click.''
直到听到「卡拉」 一声.
抱歉, 朗尼特.
Sorry, Ronette.
Ronette,
朗尼特,
can you hear me?
能听见我说话吗?
好.
Okay.
l'm glad you're feeling better.
很高兴你好点了.
l don't want to upset you,
but we need your help.
我并不想打搅你
当我们需要你的帮助.
我有一些人像素描
要给你辨认.
l'm gonna show you some sketches.
我们需要知道
你见过哪几个.
We need to know
if you've seen these men before.
We need to know if these
are the men that hurt you, okay?
是不是他们
袭击你的, 可以?
认得这个男人吗?
Do you recognize this man?
ls this the man that hurt you?
是他袭击你的吗?
朗尼特.
Ronette.
Train. Train.
火车. 火车.
- 朗尼特?
- 火-- 车, 火车.
- Ronette?
- Tr-- Train, train.
- Nurse. Right away.
- Train?
- 叫护士. 快.
- 火车?
- 火--
- Train?
- Tra--
Are you in the train car? Train car?
你在火车里吗? 火车吗?
Train, train, train!
火车, 火车, 火车!
是, 是, 是! 火车!
Yeah, yeah, yeah! Train!
Okay, okay. Stay calm.
好, 好. 冷静.
火车, 火车.
Train, train.
本哥,
我们有两本帐本,
Brother Ben,
we've got two ledgers
and one smoked cheese pig.
和一只烟熏芝士猪.
你要烧哪一样?
Which one do we burn?
And it ain't gonna be my pig.
不会是我的芝士猪吧.
The real ledger shows the mill
slowly seeking into bankruptcy,
这个真帐本详细的记录了
锯木厂破产的实际情况,
masterminded by Catherine.
凯萨琳一手策划的.
The one she faked,
for public consumption,
这本假的,
是公开资料,
好让人觉得
它仍在盈利.
shows the mill
turning a healthy profit.
So which one do we burn?
那到底烧哪一本?
凯瑟琳死了,
Catherine's dead,
we put all of our money on Josie,
我们把钱全压在乔西身上了,
Catherine takes the fall for the fire,
凯瑟琳做纵火案的替罪羊,
乔西得到保险赔偿,
Josie pockets the insurance money,
sells us the mill and the land and--
No, wait a minute.
把锯木厂连地皮一起卖给我们，然后--
不是, 等等.
她必须先让亲爱的皮特
签字才行.
First she has to get dear Pete
to sign on the dotted line.
Why does Pete have to sign?
为什么要皮特签字?
安德鲁的遗嘱定下
凯瑟琳或她的继承人同意签字才能卖.
Andrew's will calls for Catherine
or her heirs to approve of any sale.
那到底要烧哪一本?
So which one do we burn?
一旦乔西把她卖给我们,
Once Josie sells us the mill,
如果地价上涨
我们就可以买个好价钱了.
we could get a better price
if it appears to be more profitable.
那把真的那本烧了吧.
So we burn the real one.
但另一方面,
On the other hand,
the real one would hold up
under any future scrutiny.
万一以后有什么变化
真的那本就能派上用场.
Depending upon how one looks
at the situation, it appears...
要视情况而定
兵来将挡，水来土掩...
...they both have merit.
...看来两本都有价值.
就是.
l know.
或许两本都应该烧掉.
Maybe we should burn both of them.
lt looks like we are 1 00 percent certain
that we're not sure.
唯一可以肯定地就是
我们什么都不肯定.
杰, 肯定要
烧掉一些东西的.
Jer, obviously something
requires burning.
要不就
烧你的烟熏芝士猪,
And since we don't wanna set fire
to your smoked cheese pig,
我们为什么不...
why don't we...
...尝尝这个?
...try these?
棉花糖!
Marshmallows!
本, 那些烧烤叉在哪儿?
Ben, where are those hickory sticks?
玛格利特,
很高兴你常来.
Margaret,
it's always very nice to see you.
但如果你要
吐黏糊糊的口香糖时,
But if you're gonna spit
your sticky pitch gum out in the diner,
请吐到烟灰缸里,
please use an ashtray,
and not the counter or the booth
like you did last time?
不要像上次那样
在柜台和卡座里乱吐，好么?
我有一只熊掌.
l'll have a bear claw.
你胸口上戴的那些东西
很闪亮.
You wear shiny objects
on your chest.
是, 是的.
Yes, l do.
你感到骄傲吗?
Are you proud?
不, 没什么好骄傲的.
骄兵必败.
No, achievement is its own reward.
Pride obscures it.
加奶精吗?
Cream?
我的灵木有话要和你说.
My log has something to tell you.
你想知道吗?
Do you know it?
l don't believe
we've been introduced.
你还没介绍
我们认识呢.
l do not introduce the log.
我从来不介绍我的灵木.
你能听见它说什么?
Can you hear it?
不, 夫人, 我听不见.
No, ma'am, l cannot.
l will translate.
那我翻译.
去送消息.
Deliver the message.
你懂吗?
Do you understand?
是的, 夫人. 我想我懂了.
Yes, ma'am. As a matter of fact l do.
今天没信, 布伦南副警长.
No messages, Deputy Brennan.
听我说, 露西·默恩.
只管听我说.
Listen to me, Lucy Moran.
You just listen.
科玛纽精子银行
有一次在招捐精志愿者,
When the Tacoma Sperm Bank
was looking for donors,
于是我去了.
naturally l applied.
我觉得这是市民的责任,
而且我喜欢鲸鱼.
lt's my civic duty,
and l like whales.
但是一个常规体检
显示我有不育症.
A routine physical examination
revealed that l'm sterile.
当然, 刚开始
我想可能搞错了
Sure, l thought it meant
l didn't have to take a bath,
但后来医生亲口告诉我的.
but the doctors told me the truth.
他们说我不会有小孩的.
They told me l can't have babies.
所以, 我现在想知道
你为什么会怀上，怎么怀上的?
So, what l wanna know now is
why you're having one and how?
你好, 汉克.
Hello, Hank.
露西一定和你说过
要在外面等吧, 呵?
l bet Lucy asked you
to wait outside, huh?
大概说过吧.
Might've.
你知道,把雄鹿杀了
作标本真太可怕了, 哈里.
You know,
that's an awfully cute buck, Harry.
别浪费时间了.
Let's not waste our time.
那好吧.
Okay.
Why don't you...
为什么你就...
...不能乖乖的签了它呢?
...just sign in like a good boy?
规规矩矩的
过好下一周.
Keep your nose clean
for another week.
又见到你了，真好.
lt's really nice to see you again.
有意思.
lnteresting piece of work.
你和汉克
认识多久了?
How long were you
and Hank friends?
We grew up together.
我们从小一起长大.
汉克以前也是
书屋会的成员.
Hank used to be
a Bookhouse Boy.
Back then...
当时...
...Hank was one of the best of us.
...汉克是我们中间最棒的一个.
Sheriff Truman, I have Ben Horne
on the phone for you.
杜鲁门警长, 本·荷恩
找你.
要我帮你
转进来吗?
Would you like me
to transfer him to you?
哦, 不是转他是转电话?
Well, not him but his phone call?
接进来, 露西.
Put him on, Lucy.
荷恩,先生 我是露西.
Mr. Horne, this is Lucy.
现在帮你转接到
杜鲁门警长的办公室.
I'm gonna transfer you now
into Sheriff Truman's office.
他现在和
特派探员戴尔·库珀一起.
He's in there with
SpeciaI Agent DaIe Cooper.
Okay, so hold on.
好, 请稍等.
杜鲁门警长,
本·荷恩转进来了.
Sheriff Truman,
l've transferred Ben Horne to you.
正在闪灯的
那条线.
It's the Iine with the Iight
that's bIinking.
- 是, 本.
- 哈里...
- Yes, Ben.
- Harry...
...欧蕊失踪了.
...Audrey's missing.
- 什么?
- 已经两天没见人了.
- What?
- For as much as maybe two days.
你等等.
You hold on.
欧蕊·荷恩失踪了.
Audrey Horne is missing.
一张, 还没签成的保险单.
One insurance policy, unsigned.
"没签成"?
''Un''?
那个保险经纪说
凯瑟琳觉得
The agent said that Catherine
was concerned
保单有些地方不对劲.
about certain irregularities.
比如保单的最大受益人
被改成了乔西.
Such as Josie being named
the chief beneficiary.
那个保险经纪
不应该告诉她的.
Agent wasn't supposed
to show it to her.
没关系啦, 既然凯瑟琳
都已经死于非命了,
Well, considering
Catherine's smoky fate,
我们就当给她打堂斋吧.
for our side, it's all for the best.
算了. 有得必有失.
Well. Win a few, lose a few.
快点打电话给那些
烂醉如泥的冰岛佬吧.
Let's get those pickled icemen
on the blower.
Gentlemen,
l've been giving this a lot of thought.
先生们,
我已经仔细研究过了.
因为锯木厂的火灾
合约的签署可能要推迟,
This mill fire will put contract signing
on hold for the moment,
我们得马上行动,
马上, 别让机会溜走.
so we must ensure that the moment,
our moment, does not pass us by.
l therefore recommend
we make a quick
我建议
立刻
致电冰岛
诚恳地通知他们,
but cordial follow-up phone call
to lceland,
安抚一下他们,
a little gentle handling,
也好让艾尼了解
我们会把事情及时处理好的.
let Einer know
that we're right on top of this thing.
我们会摆平的.
We can handle that.
请找艾尼·霍尔森，我是本·荷恩.
Ben Horne for Einer Thorson.
你看,我们心有灵犀 .
Now, this is a coincidence.
艾尼.
Einer.
你说什么?
What's that?
你是怎么知道火灾的事?
Where did you hear about it?
是帕尔默先生
打电话告诉你的?
Mr. Palmer called
to tell you about the fire?
不, 不, 绝对不是
什么天灾人祸.
No, no, l wouldn't call it
a disaster at all.
只是发展过程里的,
一个小小意外.
lt's just one of those things,
an unfortunate development.
但我可以向你保证, 艾尼,
But l assure you, Einer,
无论发生什么
都不会影响我们的发展大计.
that it in no way
will affect our development plans.
艾尼，我是杰利·荷恩.
Jerry Horne here, Einer.
上帝保佑，我们将全力以赴.
Full speed ahead.
是, 是的, 当然, 艾尼.
Yes, yes, of course, Einer.
我们会尽快把详细报告
传真给你.
We will fax all pertinent details
to you.
是, 是的, 我保证.
Yes, yes, l promise.
听我说, 希望你别为这事
心烦意乱.
Listen, l don't want you to worry
your attractive blond head about this.
艾尼, 我还要开会, 先这样.
Einer, l'm in a meeting, gotta go.
利兰?
Leland?
利兰, 我看这样吧.
Leland, here's an idea.
合约的事
你就先别管了,
Let's take you off of
damage control,
不如你先帮我
处理一下其他事务吧.
let you concentrate on something
that you can handle.
填填那些纳税申报单之类的.
Like my tax return.
我认识他.
l know him.
什么?
Excuse me?
我祖父在珍珠湖
有座避暑山庄.
My grandfather's summer house
on Pearl Lakes.
他就住在隔壁.
He lived right next door.
我那时还很小.
l was just a little boy.
但我认得他.
But l know him.
我得马上去
通报警长.
l've gotta tell the sheriff
about this right away.
杰利...
Jerry...
...拜托你杀了利兰吧.
...please kill Leland.
这是真的吗, 本,
ls this real, Ben,
只是个变态的梦吧?
还是我们都疯了?
or some strange and
twisted dream?
那颗子弹嵌在里欧的脊椎骨里--
The bullet lodged in Leo's spine--
别担心, 雪莉, 会好起来的.
lt's all right, Shelly, come on.
The bullet lodged in his spine,
but we removed it successfully.
子弹是嵌在他的脊椎骨里,
但我们已经成功把它取出来了.
至于会不会瘫痪,
现在还很难说.
As for possible paralysis,
it's too early to tell.
本来还想动一次手术,
Leo lost a lot of blood,
但里欧已经
失血过多.
most of it before we had a chance
to operate.
导致脑部严重缺氧
这种昏迷状态下再动手术,
l fear the resulting oxygen deprivation
starved his brain,
我怕他的身体承受不了.
induced the coma you see here.
他成了植物人?
ls he a vegetable?
那他会痛苦吗?
ls he in pain?
他感觉不到痛苦.
He's not in pain.
很难解释, 不是你想像的那样.
Beyond that, it's hard to say.
你能治好他吗?
Can you make him better?
目前我们只能维持他的现状.
We can maintain his current state.
打流质营业, 用维生仪器.
Offer nutrition, life-support.
除此之外
我们只能等待.
Beyond that the only ally
we have is time.
l'm sorry, Shelly.
我也很难过, 雪莉.
我也是.
Me too.
他会坐牢吗?
Are they gonna put him in prison?
我知道他现在
是几个重案的嫌疑人.
l know he's a suspect
in several felonies.
看来这牢
他是坐定了.
l guess at the moment
he's kind of in prison anyway.
嗯, 是啊.
Yes, he is.
来吧, 我还是先
送你回房收拾吧.
Come on, l'll take you back
to your room.
诺玛来接你回家了
她在楼下等着呢.
Norma's waiting downstairs
to drive you home.
你好, 双峰镇警察局.
Hello, Twin Peaks Sheriff's Station.
请问哪里找?
Who may l say is calling, please?
不好意思, 你要告诉我
你的名字
l'm sorry, l can't connect you
with Sheriff Truman
否则，电话不能
转给杜鲁门警长.
unless you tell me
what your name is.
你不能说?
You won't?
很抱歉, 那我不能转给
杜鲁门警长
l'm sorry, but l can't connect you
with Sheriff Truman
除非告诉我你名字.
unless you tell me who you are.
实在很抱歉 ,
你再不说我就要挂机了.
l'm terribly sorry,
but l'm going to have to hang up now.
嘿, 我来送吧.
Hey, l'll take it from here.
不. 不, 你不行.
No. No, you won't.
没事, 怕什么.
No, it's okay.
那好吧, 小心别打烂了.
Okay, but watch out for this one.
我会的.
Okay.
干嘛把吸尘器关了?
Why is the vacuum cleaner off?
看看这些脚指头.
Look at those toes.
脚指头怎么啦?
What toes?
我送冰来了.
l brought the ice.
送来啦? 我的小雪人.
Frosty? My little snowman.
怪不得凉飕飕的.
l feel a cold front moving in.
嗨呀, 艾默里.
还记得我吗?
Hi, Emory.
You remember me?
看起来
你很会享受嘛, 哼?
lt really looks like you got yourself
in a fix here, huh?
好, 猜猜看.
Well, guess what.
现在我要给你讲一个
很好听的童话故事. 准备好了吗?
l'm going to tell you a nice
little bedtime story. Are you ready?
很久很久以前
一个很傻很天真地女孩, 叫小红帽--
Once upon a time there was
a sweet, innocent girl named Red--
就是我.
That's me.
--然后她碰到了大坏狼--
也就是你.
--and she met a bad old wolf--
That's you.
--她狠狠的揍了大坏狼一顿之后
还告诉了她爸爸.
--and she kicked the crap out of that
wolf and she told her daddy all about it.
和警察叔叔,
Then she told the police,
结果又老又丑的大坏狼
被判刑坐一百万年牢.
and the bad old wolf
went to jail for a million years.
- 你到底想怎样?
- 把你知道事的都告诉我.
- What do you want?
- l want to know everything you know.
香水专柜, 劳拉·帕尔默,
朗尼特·珀拉斯奇和单眼杰克赌场.
Perfume counter, Laura Palmer,
Ronette Pulaski and One-Eyed Jack's.
你疯了.
You're insane.
我疯了?
l'm insane?
听着, 我是欧蕊·荷恩
我爱干嘛就干嘛.
Well, l'm Audrey Horne
and l get what l want.
- 懂了没?
- 是, 听到了.
- Understand?
- Yes, all right.
我替单眼杰克赌场
的老板干活.
l work for the owner
of One-Eyed Jack's.
- 谁是老板?
- 我替单眼杰克赌场
- Who is?
- l work for the owner
- 的老板干活.
- 他是谁?
- of One-Eyed Jack's.
- Who is?
你爸爸.
Your father.
赌场是他的.
真见鬼, 所有东西都是他的.
He owns it all.
Hell, he owns everything.
我负责把香水专柜
的女生介绍进来.
l run girls through
the perfume counter.
也包括朗尼特和劳拉.
l recruited Ronette and Laura.
- 劳拉在这呆过?
- 有一个周末.
- Did Laura come here?
- One weekend.
她嗑了药.
She was using drugs.
我们就把她扔了出去.
之后再没见过她了, 我发誓.
We threw her out.
l never saw her again, l swear.
我爸爸知道
劳拉在这呆过吗?
Did my father know
that Laura was here?
是的, 是的, 他当然知道.
Yes, yes, he did.
荷恩先生经常
来和她们玩.
Mr. Horne makes it his business
to entertain all the girls.
她知道是我爸的吗?
Did she know he owned this place?
什么?
Owned what?
- 赌场!
- 是! 是. 有可能知道.
- One-Eyed Jack's!
- Yes! Yes. Probably she did.
劳拉总有法子的.
Laura always got her way.
懂吗?
Understand?
就跟你一样.
Just like you.
干嘛不换个台.
Why don't you change the station.
这个好.
That's good.
唔.
Yeah.
我打过电话给保险公司了.
l made the call.
我说是里欧的堂兄.
Told them l was Leo's cousin.
里欧现在残废了
Leo gets his disability
只要他监狱外服刑.
就可以得到一大笔赔偿金, 知道吗，雪莉.
as long as he stays out of prison.
lt's a lot of money, Shelly.
五千多一个月.
Over 5,000 a month.
但条件是
他必须呆在家里.
But you only get it
if he stays at home.
我可不要什么赔偿金.
我不想里欧回家.
l don't care about the money.
l don't want Leo home.
他已经半个死人了.
Leo is in dreamland.
随你摆布，塞他到墙角也行
在他耳朵上挂面包甜甜圈都行.
You can stick him in the corner
and hang doughnuts from his ears.
可是杜鲁门警长
想我出庭作证人.
Sheriff Truman wants me
to make a statement.
别傻了. 瞧, 他们怎么能强迫你
去指证自己的丈夫呢.
No way. Look, they can't force you
to testify against your husband.
你要做的
是把里欧接回家,
All you gotta do is get Leo home,
等着收支票享福去.
sit and collect the checks.
那是里欧欠你的, 宝贝儿.
Leo owes you, baby.
该他还债了.
Now we can really make him pay.
有了这些钱
我们什么都买的起.
You want something nice?
We can buy it.
还可以周游列国,
去日光浴?
You want to go someplace special,
sit in the sun?
就靠里欧了. 明白没?
lt's on Leo. Understand?
也好吧
不用老为钱发愁.
l guess it would be nice
not to have to worry about money.
我还有很多帐单没还呢.
l have a lot of bills l have to pay.
帐单? 想那个干嘛.
我现在讨论的是一个美好的未来.
Bills? Forget about bills.
l'm talking about a new way of life.
共同奋斗?
Together?
你说呢?
What do you think?
我现在只想爽爽.
l think l wanna get comfortable.
那得尝尝我爸传给我的那杆大烟枪了.
That's why l got my dad's Continental.
波比·布里格斯,
看我不把你生吞了.
Bobby Briggs,
l'm gonna eat you up.
来吞啊?
Promise?
你给我走着瞧.
Just watch me.
黛安, 今天接到
好几个坏消息.
Diane, l received
some very bad news today.
伟顿·厄尔失踪了.
Windom Earle has vanished.
我的前搭档
莫名其妙的消失
The disappearance
of my former partner
着实让人感到不安.
is extremely troubling.
欧蕊·荷恩
也失踪了.
l also learned that Audrey Horne
is missing.
我完全没料到
欧蕊会失踪.
Audrey's absence touches me
in ways l could not predict.
除了她的
那张笑脸,
l find myself thinking not of clues
or of evidence,
其他线索我毫无头绪.
but of the content of her smile.
是谁?
Who is it?
库珀探员，是我，布里格斯少校.
lt's Major Briggs, Agent Cooper.
马上来.
Just a moment.
- 少校.
- 我可以进来吗?
- Major.
- May l come in?
请进.
Please.
给你带个口信.
l have a message for you.
谁的口信?
From whom?
基于我工作的特殊性
恕我不能直说.
l'm not at liberty
to reveal the nature of my work.
知者不能言
有时确实让我很痛苦.
This secrecy pains me
from time to time.
任何官僚制度下
都有一套保护自身秘密的系统
Any bureaucracy
that functions in secret
可它又反过来增加了更多不可告人的腐败秘密.
inevitably lends itself to corruption.
但我发过誓
必须要捍卫它.
But these rules l have pledged
to uphold.
我始终相信有些信念神圣不可侵犯.
l believe a pledge is sacred.
作为联邦政府的
Speaking as a man
公务员和代言人
我理解你.
and a fellow employee
of the federal government, so do l.
好了, 我或许只能透露这些给你:
Well, l may reveal this much:
在我执行的众多任务中
Among my many tasks
其中一项就是对
瞄准外层太空银河系
is the maintenance
of deep-space monitors
的监测器进行维修和保养.
aimed at galaxies beyond our own.
我们的日常事务
就是接收些五花八门的信号,
We routinely receive
various communications,
也有些太空垃圾,
然后进行解码和检测.
space garbage,
to decode and examine.
你看，它们是这样子的.
They look something like this.
lt's radio waves and gibberish,
Agent Cooper.
无线电波和一些乱七八糟的信息代码,
库珀探员.
知道周四晚.
Till Thursday night.
应该是周五的凌晨.
Friday morning to be exact.
就是我中枪的那晚.
Around the time that l was shot.
当晚的资料分析把我们吓了一跳.
The readout took us by surprise.
一排接一排讥哩咕噜的鬼话之后.
Row after row of gibberish.
突然出现了这个...
And all of a sudden...
"不要给猫头鹰的外表迷惑了."
''The owls are not what they seem.''
为什么告诉我这些?
Why did you bring this to me?
因为那天凌晨之后...
Because later in the morning...
"库珀...
''Cooper...
...库珀. 库珀."
...Cooper. Cooper.''
我的天啊.
My God.
刚刚唱的不错.
我们再来一次吧.
That was really good.
Let's try it again.
只有你和我
Just you and I
在一起
Together
永远
Forever
相爱
In Iove
只有你
Just you
- 和我
- And I
- 只有你
- Just you
和我
And I
- 和我
- And I
- 在一起
- Together
- 永远
- 永远的
- Forever
- 相爱
- In Iove
相爱
In Iove
- 相爱
- In Iove
我们一同漫步在
We go stroIIing together
爱意中
In Iove
我们漫步到永远
We go stroIIing forever
- 只有你
- Just you
- 和我
- And I
只有你和我
Just you and I
和我
And I
在一起
Together
直到永远
Forever
在爱意里
In Iove
只有你
Just you
和我
And I
只有你
Just you
和我
And I
只有你
Just you
和我
And I
只有你
Just you
和我
And I
只有你
Just you
唐娜.
Donna.
唐娜, 怎么了?
Donna, what's wrong?
没什么.
Nothing.
唐娜?
Donna?
唐娜, 到底怎么了?
Donna, what's going on?
我只是有点激动, 詹姆斯.
l'm trembling, James.
你让我好激动.
You made me.
唐娜.
Donna.
唐娜?
Donna?
什么事?
Yes?
你的电话
是哈罗德·史密斯.
There's a telephone call for you
from a Harold Smith.
哦, 好的. 我在走廊听.
Oh, okay. l'll get it in the hallway.
好了, 爸. 我在听呢.
Okay, Dad. l got it.
好的, 宝贝儿.
Okay, sweetheart.
你好?
Hello?
史密斯先生?
Mr. Smith?
我收到了.
l received yours.
我想和你当面谈谈.
l wanted to talk to you.
能见面吗?
We can meet?
好.
Okay.
不要给猫头鹰的外表迷惑了.
The owls are not what they seem.
劳拉!
Laura!
库珀探员.
Agent Cooper.
- 是我, 欧蕊.
- 鸥蕊?
- lt's me, Audrey.
- Audrey?
你在哪儿?
Where are you?
你为什么没有来?
Why aren't you here?
欧蕊, 现在没时间
玩过家家.
Audrey, this is no time
for schoolgirl games.
我要你马上回家.
l want you home now.
我看到你穿礼服的样子.
l saw you in your tuxedo.
太帅了，就像电影明星.
You look like a movie star.
欧蕊,
如果你是碰到什么麻烦的话--
Audrey,
if you're in any kind of troubIe--
我是遇到麻烦了
但我会马上回家的.
l am in trouble
but l'm gonna come home now.
欧蕊? 欧蕊?
Audrey? Audrey?
麻烦大了, 荷恩小姐?
Trouble, Miss Horne?
知道有多大吗?
You don't know what trouble is.
总之会很大很大....
Not by a long shot.